Guide to the Gil Green Papers TAM.095
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: FBI and Prison Files, 1939-1993; 11.5 Linear Feet
  - Subseries IVC: Files by Topic, 1925-1980; 10.5 Linear Feet
    - Chicago FBI Office Files - Various Individuals, 1944-1949 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Communist Activity - American Youth Congress, Anti-draft Activities, and Other Organizations, 1949-1972 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Communist Activity - Chicago Families of Smith Act Victims and CPUSA May Day Rally, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Communist Activity - Civil Rights Congress and Various Individuals, 1944-1951 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Communist Activity - Communist Political Association, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Communist Activity - Communist Political Association and Communist Infiltration, 1944, 1954-1959 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Communist Activity - Communist Political Association and CPUSA, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Communist Activity - Communist Political Association of New York State, 1944, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Communist Activity - Communist Publications, 1938-1944 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Communist Activity - CPUSA and Affiliated Individuals, 1956-1965 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Communist Activity - CPUSA, American Youth Congress, and Others (Mid-West), 1945-1951 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Communist Activity - CPUSA National Emergency Convention; Peace Movement, 1940, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Communist Activity - FBI Reports on Communist Trends and National Non-Partisan Committee, 1945-1949 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Communist Activity - Fish Committee Report and Investigation of Communist Propaganda, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Communist Activity - Gil Green and World Peace Council, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Communist Activity - Gil Green, Communist Political Association, and Other Groups, 1939-1961 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Communist Activity - Gil Green, Young Communist League and Others, 1945-1967 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Communist Activity - Individuals and People's Coalition for Peace and Justice, 1943-1952 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Communist Activity - Infiltration and Regional Activity, 1941-1965 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Communist Activity - National Conference for New Politics and CPUSA National Convention, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Communist Activity - New York Region, Jacob Satchel, and Other Individuals, 1942-1949 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Communist Activity - Report on National Peace and Justice Conference, 1971 June 25-27 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Communist Activity - Various Individuals, 1940-1956 (Box 10, Folder 14-18)
    - Communist Activity - Various Individuals and Regional Activity, 1943-1972 (Box 10, Folder 19-22)
    - Communist Activity - Various Organizations and Individuals, 1942-1972 (Box 10, Folder 23-28)
    - Communist Activity - Various Regional Offices, 1944-1952 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Communist Activity - Vito Marcantonio, New York, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Communist Activity - Young Communist League, 1925-1942 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Communist Activity - Young Communist League and Other Groups, 1940-1951 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Communist Activity - Young Communist League, Communist Political Association, and Peace Movement, 1937-1951 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Communist Activity - Young Communist League and the Youth Movement, 1938-1940 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Communist Activity - Young Communist League and Communist Infiltration, 1942-1967 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Communist Activity - Young Communist League and Other Organizations, 1945-1948 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Communist Activity - Youth Organizations, CPUSA in NY, and Upstate Federation for Peace and Freedom, 1941-1956, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Anti-War Movement and Political Demonstrations, 1941-1972 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Art Freeman and Doris Corey, 1939, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Civil Rights Congress, 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Civil Rights Congress and Domanul American, 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Committee to Defend the Bill of Rights and National Partisan Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Harry Greenberg, World Peace Council, and Other Individuals, 1944-1971 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Langston Hughes and Other Individuals, 1947-1951 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - March on Washington Against the War in Vietnam and Various Individuals, 1941-1965 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Morning Freight Association and Various Individuals, 1950-1954 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - National Conference for New Politics, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - National Conference for New Politics and Subversive Literature, 1937-1965 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Nationality Groups, 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - New World Review, 1970 June-August (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - People's Coalition for Peace and Justice, 1945-1950, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - People's Coalition for Peace and Justice and Anti-Vietnam Protests, 1970-1974 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - People's Coalition for Peace and Justice, Anti-War Organizations, 1939-1971 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - People's Coalition for Peace and Justice and the Spring Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 1952-1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - People's Coalition for Peace and Justice, Robert Thompson, and Others, 1949-1973 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Student Movement and National Conference for New Politics, 1965-1967 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Theresa Elrich and Others, 1945-1950 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Various Individuals, 1944-1969 (Box 11, Folder 21-25)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Various Individuals in Chicago, Detroit, and Baltimore, 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Various Organizations and Individuals, 1942-1972 (Box 11, Folder 27-36)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - Various Organizations and Individuals in the North East and Mid-West, 1943-1965 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Communist Affiliation and Subversive Activity - William Lazar, Le Roy Hand Wood, and Others, 1944-1952 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Communist Infiltration - Progressive Party and International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers, 1947-1955 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - CPUSA - Brief on Smith Act Investigations and Party Activity at Regional Offices, 1948-1968 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - CPUSA - Brief to Establish Illegal Status, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 3-10)
    - CPUSA - Buffalo Field Division; People's Coalition for Peace and Justice, 1942, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - CPUSA - Chicago Regional Office and Smith Act Trial of National Leadership, 1949-1951 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - CPUSA - Chicago and Buffalo Offices, 1944-1948 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - CPUSA - Communist Literature and Party Activities in California, 1945-1946, 1960-1965 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - CPUSA - Counter Intelligence Program (COINTELPRO), 1950-1963 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - CPUSA - Education and Affiliated Individuals, 1949-1954 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - CPUSA - Espionage and Smith Act Fugitives, 1941-1951 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - CPUSA - FBI Quarterly Reports, 1944-1966 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - CPUSA - General Subversive Activities, 1940-1971 (Box 12, Folder 19-23)
    - CPUSA - General Subversive Activities, 1948-1956 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - CPUSA - General Subversive Activity and American Youth Congress, 1944-1963 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - CPUSA - General Subversive Activities, 1938-1943 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - CPUSA - Gil Green and Affiliated Individuals, 1949-1952 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
    - CPUSA - Gil Green and Anne Green, 1949-1975 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - CPUSA - Gil Green and National Committee, 1968-1971 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - CPUSA - Gil Green, National Council, and Affiliated Individual (includes file on Helen O. Green), 1949-1974 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - CPUSA - Gil Green and Underground Activities, 1949-1953 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - CPUSA - National Conventions and Leadership, 1944-1967 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - CPUSA - National Leadership and National Convention, 1942-1961 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - CPUSA - Newspaper Clippings, 1944-1961 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - CPUSA - New York Bureau File, 1940-1950 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - CPUSA - New York Field Division, 1942-1944 (Box 13, Folder 14-15)
    - CPUSA - New York Field Division (many pages missing), 1944 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - CPUSA - New York File, 1945-1949 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - CPUSA - New York, Quarterly Reports, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - CPUSA - Regional Offices, 1941-1963 (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
    - CPUSA - Regional Offices and Affiliated Individuals, 1941-1976 (Box 13, Folder 21-25)
    - CPUSA - Reports on Party Leadership, 1944-1967 (Box 13, Folder 26-27)
    - CPUSA - Reports on National Committee of CPUSA, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - CPUSA - Smith Act Trial Reports and Affiliated Individuals, 1944-1956 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - CPUSA - Washington DC and Chicago Field Offices, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - CPUSA - Reports on Activity of Party Leadership and Smith Act Defendants, 1948-1967 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - CPUSA - Youth Matters, 1942, 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - CPUSA Activity and Affiliated Individuals, 1945-1949 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - CPUSA and Affiliated Individuals (includes report on People's Coalition for Peace and Justice), 1948, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - CPUSA and the Young Communist League, 1941-1952 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - FBI Clipping Files - Communist Activity, 1942-1949 (Box 14, Folder 4-8)
    - FBI Clipping Files - Communist Party Leadership and Elections, 1942-1943 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - FBI Clipping Files - Gil Green and Smith Act Trial, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - FBI Clipping Files - Smith Act Trial, 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 11-14)
    - Gil Green - Political Activities and FOIA Requests, 1976-1980 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Smith Act - Seditious Activities of Gil Green, 1945-1962 (Box 14, Folder 16-17)
    - Smith Act Cases - "Trial of the Twelve", 1949 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Smith Act Cases Defendants Amnesty Campaign, 1949-1957 (Box 14, Folder 19-21)
    - Smith Act Cases Defendants Amnesty Campaign - Gil Green and Henry Winston, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Smith Act Defendants - Gil Green, 1944-1951 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Smith Act Fugitives; Communist Activity, 1941, 1950-1953 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Anticipation of Green's Surrender, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - CPUSA Members, 1951-1955 (Box 14, Folder 26-29)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - CPUSA Members; People's Coalition for Peace and Justice, 1949-1951, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Gil Green, 1951-1956 (Box 14, Folder 31-37)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Gil Green and Communist Underground Activities, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Gil Green and Henry Winston, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Gil Green and Other CPUSA Members, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 3-6)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Gil Green in New York City, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Gil Green Surrender to FBI, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Gil Green; Green Communist Activity, 1944, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Gus Hall; Communist Affiliated Individuals, 1944-1953 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Reports and Notes Regarding Green's Location, 1952-1954 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Smith Act Fugitives - Trial Summary, Contempt of Court, and Communist Subversion, 1946-1954 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Smith Act Trials - Attorney General Correspondence, 1949-1960 (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
    - Smith Act Trials - Briefs on Trial Proceedings, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 16-24)
    - Smith Act Trials - Briefs on Trial Proceedings; Communist Infiltration, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Smith Act Trials - Briefs on Trial Proceedings; SAC Memoranda, 1949, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Smith Act Trials - Briefs on Trial Proceedings and Testimony, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Smith Act Trials - Clippings, 1948-1949 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    - Smith Act Trials - CPUSA Brief and Evidence Summaries, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Smith Act Trials - Evidence Against CPUSA Leaders, 1928-1949 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
    - Smith Act Trials - Evidence and Testimony, 1942-1949 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Smith Act Trials - Gil Green Testimony, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Smith Act Trials - Henry Winston Testimony, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Smith Act Trials - Jurors, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Smith Act Trials - Opposition, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Smith Act Trials - Prosecution of CPUSA National Board Members, 1942-1951 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Smith Act Trials - Testimony and Evidence, 1936, 1949, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Smith Act Trials - Testimony of Yolanda Hall and Edward Joseph Chaka; Other CPUSA Activity, 1942-1965 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Smith Act Trials - Vito Marcantonio and Opposition, 1949-1951 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Smith Act Trials - William G. Cummings and Herbert Philbrick Testimony, 1949, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 18-20)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (Los Angeles) - Surveillance of Gil Green and CPUSA, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (Los Angeles) - Surveillance of Gil Green and Political Affairs Forum, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (Los Angeles) - Surveillance of Gil Green, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York) - Reports on Articles Written by Gil Green, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York) - Reports on Gil Green and CPUSA, 1972-1978 (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York) - Reports on Gil Green and People's Coalition for Peace and Justice, 1959-1973 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York) - Reports on People's Coalition for Peace and Justice and the National Conference for New Politics, 1953-1967 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York) - Surveillance of Gil Green, 1967-1978 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York) - Surveillance of Gil Green and CPUSA, 1941-1968 (Box 17, Folder 11-14)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York) - Surveillance Logs and Weekly Reports on Gil Green, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York) - Weekly Reports on Gil Green, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York and Buffalo) - Surveillance of Gil Green and CPUSA, 1966-1972 (Box 17, Folder 17-28)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York and Buffalo) - Surveillance of Gil Green and Reports on the New Left, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York and Chicago) - Reports Regarding Gil Green's Release from Prison, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York and Chicago) - Surveillance of Gil Green, 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York and Chicago) - Surveillance of Gil Green and Reports on Various Activist Organizations, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York, Chicago, and Los Angeles) - Surveillance of Gil Green, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York and Los Angeles) - Surveillance of Gil Green and Reports on Smith Act Fugitives, 1953-1965 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York and Los Angeles) - Surveillance Logs and Weekly Reports on Gil Green, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York, Philadelphia, and Boston) - Reports on Gil Green and CPUSA, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (New York and Various Cities) - Reports on Gil Green, CPUSA, and Other Organizations, 1958-1959 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (Various Cities) - Reports on Communist Activities of Gil Green, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Special Agent in Charge Memoranda (Various Cities) - Reports on Gil Green and CPUSA, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Surveillance Log - Gil Green, Joseph Kirschner, and Danny Green, 1951-1966 (Box 18, Folder 6)